<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>

<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
   
    <title>avinash.me</title>
   
   <link>http://avinash.me</link>
   <description>Doodles and lot more!</description>
   <language>en-us</language>
   <managingEditor>Avinash</managingEditor>
   <atom:link href="rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
   
	
		<item>
  <title>PHP Developers Meetup #6</title>
  <link>http://avinash.me/2013/04/07/php-developers-meetup-6.html</link>
  <author>Avinash Kundailya</author>
  <pubDate>2013-04-07T00:00:00+05:45</pubDate>
  <guid>http://avinash.me/2013/04/07/php-developers-meetup-6.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p><img alt='PHP Developers Meetup' src='http://img145.imageshack.us/img145/2388/4tvefoo.jpg' /></p>

<p>This is my first post regarding the PHP Developers Meetup we have in Kathmandu almost every month. Yesterday, we had the sixth iteration of the meetup and it went pretty well. We started with a 10 minute delay because we Nepalese are used to Nepali Time :-P, but on a serious note I wish we could start right on time moving forward.</p>

<p>I took the first session and had planned to discuss about Open Web Applications and how awesome it is. I had more memes and trolls and less slides, most of my talk was based on showing how easy it was to create an Application using the open web and the whole concept behind it. I showed the same app runnning on OSX, a nexus 7 and in the browser (of-course) and that made it much easier to explain the power of it. I guess the talk went pretty well and people would be interested in exploring more and creating applications using the open web. <a href='http://avinash.me/talks/openwebapp-phpmeet6/'>(Slides)</a> <a href='http://github.com/hardfire/losh'>(Github Source for LoadShedding Application)</a></p>

<p><img alt='The web is the platform' src='http://img833.imageshack.us/img833/9665/zgxakzf.jpg' /></p>

<p>Prashish then talked about creating a real time dashboard using Node.js, Angular.JS and D3.js. The session was quite informative and people were quite keen to discuss about scalability and there were some suggestion on how it could be made more polished. He had no demo to show as it was still a WIP, but we hope to have a look at the finished product in the next meetup.</p>

<p>Next, Gaurav talked about virtualization and how developers could harness it to create a seamless development enviornment. Between the talk (when virtual machines were being cloned), we had a good disucssion about vagrant and how people were using it. Being a sysadmin, he did give everyone suggestions on different ways you could host and why an EC2 instance could be much better an option than a VPS.</p>

<p>Finally, since we had an open-discussion session between the virtualization talk, we instead talked about how developers were using email and processing email to provide a service. In the process we touched on how mailinator was implemented and how craigslist implements its email thingy. Overall I must say it was a fruitful developer meet. Next month we would have a hacknight, so gear up and start thinking about the project of the millenium :D.</p>
  ]]></description>
</item>

	

	
		<item>
  <title>My experience at #FormatAtBesu</title>
  <link>http://avinash.me/2013/04/01/experience-at-format-at-besu.html</link>
  <author>Avinash Kundailya</author>
  <pubDate>2013-04-01T00:00:00+05:45</pubDate>
  <guid>http://avinash.me/2013/04/01/experience-at-format-at-besu.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>Last week (22nd and 23rd of March 2013), I was at the super talented city of Kolkata, attending <strong>FORMAT</strong> (Firefox OS: Renaissance of Mobile App Technology) which was a part of the technical festival of Bengal Engineering and Science University (also known as BESU). This was a two day event completely focused on developing web applications which would also work on Firefox OS.</p>

<p><img alt='Sayak Talking about Firefox OS' src='http://img689.imageshack.us/img689/8202/format3.jpg' /></p>

<h3 id='day_1'>Day 1</h3>

<p>The first day of the event was aimed at giving the audience an idea of mozilla, the mozilla community and Firefox OS, ofcourse. Vineel started by talking about mozilla and the community, Sayak continued by introducing the idea of Firefox OS and why it was required, Soumya then took on the stage and discussed some technical details about the platform and eventually Robin, Sayak, Biraj and me gave some demos on firefox OS application and the process of writing a basic &#8220;hello world&#8221; application. The talks went pretty well but one thing that struck me was the audience. This was a very different audience, compared to other events because they were paying attention, asking questions, interacting and were actually making sense. Believe me, this rarely happens in an engineering college in India :D.</p>

<p><img alt='Serious discussion' src='http://img407.imageshack.us/img407/2742/format2.jpg' /></p>

<h3 id='day_2'>Day 2</h3>

<p>The second day was roughly divided into two parts, the hackaton and the presentations. The hackathon went pretty well and most of the attendees got a taste of, how easy it was to make an application for firefox OS using open web technologies. It was amazing to see about 30 applications being presented at the end of the day. I guess, we can say it was a win!</p>
<hr />
<p>That was all about the event. I would like to thank the FORMAT Team, especially Avik, Gaurab and Subhashish for the warm reception and managing the event in such a professional manner. Last but not the least, I got to learn a lot from Biraj, Vineel, Soumya, Robin and Sayak.</p>

<p><img alt='Kumi Doll' src='http://img248.imageshack.us/img248/4129/format4.jpg' /></p>
  ]]></description>
</item>

	

	
		<item>
  <title>Switching to Jekyll, so long WordPress</title>
  <link>http://avinash.me/2013/03/20/switching-to-jekyll.html</link>
  <author>Avinash Kundailya</author>
  <pubDate>2013-03-20T00:00:00+05:45</pubDate>
  <guid>http://avinash.me/2013/03/20/switching-to-jekyll.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>Yes! I will be moving to this blog asap, and all the content will come here too, one at a time :D</p>
  ]]></description>
</item>

	

	
		<item>
  <title>The web is the platform</title>
  <link>http://avinash.me/2013/03/18/the-web-is-the-platform.html</link>
  <author>Avinash Kundailya</author>
  <pubDate>2013-03-18T13:58:02+05:45</pubDate>
  <guid>http://avinash.me/2013/03/18/the-web-is-the-platform.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p>I have had the itch of developing a &#8220;mobile application&#8221;(with finger quotes) since quite some time now. But, the thought of learning Java or Objective C kept me waiting. With B2G, came new hopes and the idea to write your mobile applications with only web technologies. Wow, doesn&#8217;t that sound awesome :D</p>

<p><img alt='Main Screen of the App' src='http://blog.avinash.com.np/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/shot.png' /></p>

<p>Procrastination is what i do best, so I installed B2G Desktop, <a href='http://people.mozilla.com/~myk/r2d2b2g/'>r2d2b2g</a>(B2G Emulator for firefox), Firefox Nightly and waited for more than a couple of months to even start writing an application. Finally, last week, the dawn had come, a new day had started (:-P). Yes, I started writing an application for B2G. Out of all the awesome ideas, I wanted a proper loadShedding application in the browser, that i could open anytime and see the timings. 3 days of hard work, and numerous keystrokes later, the application was ready for showtime. Here is a link to the application <a href='http://avinash.me/losh'>online</a> (works only in firefox). You can <a href='http://avinash.me/losh/i.html'>install</a> it as an &#8220;open web app&#8221; too .</p>

<p><img alt='Changing groups, just a tap away' src='http://blog.avinash.com.np/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/shot2.png' /></p>

<p>This application uses angular.js (and B2G building blocks) on the front end and nothing on the backend :-P. The source is on <a href='http://github.com/hardfire/losh'>github</a> and i look forward to some &#8220;pull requests&#8221; and &#8220;stars&#8221;.</p>

<h2 id='i_want_to_make_an_app_too_how_do_i_start_'>I want to make an app too, how do i start ?</h2>

<p>Well, I am glad you asked. If you are already a web developer, tighten your belts, open your favourite text editor, push some keystrokes of awesomeness, make it responsive and at the end of it write a <a href='https://developer.mozilla.org/en/docs/Apps/Manifest'>manifest file</a>. You are done and good to go. Yes, believe me, it&#8217;s that easy. If you want the app to work offline, use <a href='http://www.html5rocks.com/en/tutorials/appcache/beginner/'>appcache</a> to save your assets offline and <a href='https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/IndexedDB'>IndexedDB</a> or<a href='https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/DOM/Storage#localStorage'>LocalStorage</a> (<a href='https://hacks.mozilla.org/2009/06/localstorage/'>another nice article</a>) to save your data. After this app, one thing that i can suggest is to design your app for offline first and then sync your data later. I started the other way round and had to take care of a lot of stuff at the end, which made no sense then, and some bugs were introduced because of that too.</p>

<p>If this is not enough to get you started, a <a href='https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Apps/Developing'>comprehensive guide</a> is available on MDN</p>

<h2 id='its_still_a_webapp_how_do_i_connect_to_the_device'>It&#8217;s still a web-app, how do i connect to the device</h2>

<p>I knew that was coming, <a href='https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/WebAPI'>WebAPIs</a> is what you are looking for. It is still a work in progress and lots of tutorials are available on <a href='https://hacks.mozilla.org/'>MozHacks</a></p>

<p>That&#8217;s all for now. Go and make something awesome and it has been validated that <strong>&#8220;THE WEB IS THE PLATFORM&#8221;</strong> <img alt='Funny thing, it even works on osx like a native app, should work on windows and linux too' src='http://blog.avinash.com.np/wp-content/uploads/2013/03/screen.jpg' /></p>
  ]]></description>
</item>

	

	
		<item>
  <title>#MozSAARC13 - learnings and takeaways</title>
  <link>http://avinash.me/2013/03/03/mozsaarc13-learnings-and-takeaways.html</link>
  <author>Avinash Kundailya</author>
  <pubDate>2013-03-03T01:32:06+05:45</pubDate>
  <guid>http://avinash.me/2013/03/03/mozsaarc13-learnings-and-takeaways.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p><img alt='Mozilla' src='http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8234/8510710320_3b69beebde_z.jpg' /></p>

<p>Last weekend (23-24 February 2013) we had the first Mozilla South Asia Inter-Community meet-up. Participants consisted of Mozillians from the South-Asian region, namely Bangladesh, India, Nepal, Pakistan and Sri Lanka. It was a great experience to meet some of the awesomest people from around the region. <a href='http://priyankaivy.blogspot.in/2013/02/mozilla-south-asia-inter-community-meet.html'>They</a> <a href='http://www.kalpapathum.blogspot.com/2013/02/mozilla-south-asia-inter-community-meet.html'>have</a> <a href='http://mythrobin.com/mozillasa13/'>already</a> <a href='http://ashickur-noor.me/mozillasa1/'>blogged</a> and shared their experiences of the event. Since, the event has been compiled in such an awesome manner already, I would like to take the time to share my learnings from the event.</p>

<p>First of all, it was great to see that we as mozilla south asian community have done some world class work in localization of Firefox, Firefox-OS and related products. The Bengali and Sinhalese versions of firefox were commendable and have been serving the purpose very well.</p>

<p>Secondly, I got to learn about the <a href='https://webmaker.org/'>Mozilla Webmaker project</a>, a project which teaches you to be able to Make something amazing with the Web and not become mere consumers(or leechers). The project consists of three high quality tools namely Popcorn, Thimble and X-Ray Goggles. Popcorn, a tool to enhance and create web videos seemed quite interesting as it pushed the limits of the web and used the real power of HTML5. Thimble and X-Ray Goggles are projects to get to a feel of literally &#8220;making&#8221; the web. Using Thimble we can create and preview html pages in an interactive online editor whereas X-Ray Goggles pushes the limits to &#8220;remix&#8221; any existing web page and recharge it with our content and imagination. More details can be found on the <a href='https://webmaker.org/'>webmaker website</a>.</p>

<p>Next up was the most anticipated project of the year, &#8220;Firefox OS&#8221;. I as a developer, am highly focused on the web as a platform and this project has made every Web Developer&#8217;s dream come true. Basically, we can create native mobile apps for the platform using the language and tools we love the most (HTML, CSS, JS on VIM :D). We got a chance to use a developer device and it seemed pretty promising.</p>

<p>Finally, the event was much better than my expectations and we came up to some concrete decisions. I look forward to supporting and working with the community for a better and an open Web. This reminds me of a line that one of my friend once told me, &#8220;Firefox is my OS&#8221;. I guess, it is pretty much true today.</p>
  ]]></description>
</item>

	

	
		<item>
  <title>Leap Motion : A big leap ?</title>
  <link>http://avinash.me/Javascript/Leap%20Motion/2013/03/02/leap-motion-a-big-leap.html</link>
  <author>Avinash Kundailya</author>
  <pubDate>2013-03-02T02:09:16+05:45</pubDate>
  <guid>http://avinash.me/Javascript/Leap%20Motion/2013/03/02/leap-motion-a-big-leap.html</guid>
  <description><![CDATA[
     <p><a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/92269244@N07/8385940323/'><img alt='Leap Motions tiny gesture controller will be available exclusively at Best Buy' src='http://farm9.staticflickr.com/8076/8385940323_7a1500210f.jpg' /></a></p>

<h2 id='what_how'>What? How?</h2>

<p>I had applied for the leap motion developer program couple of months back and was one of the lucky ones selected to receive the device. The device was mailed via fed-ex and came in a black box with just leap motion written on it. I smell apple-style there.</p>

<p>The device was quite smaller than i had anticipated, about the size of a pack of gums and it is very light of-course. It contains IR cameras that tracks fingers at a very high accuracy (1/100th of a mm).</p>

<p>I was bought by the teaser video the day i saw it. If you have not seen it yet, i suggest you have a look at it first (embedded below). That would surely get you pumped up about the leap motion controller and the power it brings with itself.</p>
<iframe frameborder='0' height='360' src='http://www.youtube.com/embed/_d6KuiuteIA' width='640'>Leap</iframe>
<h2 id='device_experience'>Device Experience</h2>

<p>The device is actually very good and precise. It lacks applications for now, and i guess that is why we have these devices shipped to us &#8220;to write some awesome apps&#8221;.</p>

<p>So, what can i do with it right away? Well, to be frank, lots of apps are being developed. The visualizer that comes with the SDK is really nice to get a feel of the device and its precision. Once again, if you have not seen the video for the visualizer, please have a look :) (embedded below)</p>

<h2 id='developers'>Developers</h2>

<p>When it comes to development, the SDK is pretty cool as it has API&#8217;s for development in C++, C#, Obj.C, Java, Python aaannd (drum roll) JavaScript. Yes, it has a WebSockets server that you can connect to and do a lot of stuff. I&#8217;ve seen some demos where developers used the $1 library to give a feel of gestures. The SDK didn&#8217;t have gesture recognition till now, but i hear the new one has some gesture awesomeness, yet to look into that. Me being a believer in &#8220;the web is the platform&#8221; makes me feel good that we can develop Leap applications using JavaScript. No, need to go through learning a whole new technology. That is a win, for sure.</p>

<h2 id='what_next'>What Next?</h2>

<p>The device will be out by May (i think). It will be different and have a better experience compared to the developer kit. I have had some ideas in mind and will start working on it in a week or so. Keep checking for updates :)</p>
  ]]></description>
</item>

	


</channel>
</rss>
